<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Outer Haven</title>
    <link>https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Outer Haven</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018 and later, all rights reserved. Theme based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gyorb/hugo-dusk&#34;&gt;hugo-dusk&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 05:05:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Programmer in Berlin: Language</title>
      <link>https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/programmer-in-berlin-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 05:05:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/programmer-in-berlin-language/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part 5 of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/programmer-in-berlin/&#34;&gt;5-part series&lt;/a&gt; detailing what I wish I had known as an&#xA;American programmer moving to Berlin. This page talks about learning the language&#xA;of the country you&amp;rsquo;re in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve saved this for last, because I think it&amp;rsquo;s the most important thing in this series. I&#xA;believe that learning the local language is the strongest driver of belonging in a new&#xA;country. It requires real effort, and you will have to prioritize it over other things,&#xA;but doing so pays off handsomely in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programmer in Berlin: Culture</title>
      <link>https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/programmer-in-berlin-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 05:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/programmer-in-berlin-culture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part 4 of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/programmer-in-berlin/&#34;&gt;5-part series&lt;/a&gt; detailing what I wish I had known as an&#xA;American programmer moving to Berlin. This page details cultural differences and things I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware of until I stumbled on them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;politics&#34;&gt;Politics&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One thing about Germany, and Europe in general, is that it&amp;rsquo;s relatively left-wing when&#xA;compared to the US. This is a&#xA;place where universal healthcare is so commonly accepted that no party &amp;ndash; not even the&#xA;super-racist party! &amp;ndash; is talking about removing it. The aforementioned super-racist&#xA;party has effectively the same political platform as the mainstream&#xA;Republican party in the US (minus the healthcare thing). Politics in Europe certainly has&#xA;its own problems, but at least in Germany there is a flourishing multi-party system that&#xA;allows for people to have some kind of choice when voting. There is even a fun website&#xA;called the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wahl-o-mat.de/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wahl-o-Mat&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;Vote-o-Matic&amp;rdquo;) that tells you which party to vote&#xA;for after&#xA;answering a series of questions. There&amp;rsquo;s also none of the Electoral College&#xA;silliness, which I won&amp;rsquo;t get into here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programmer in Berlin: Finances</title>
      <link>https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/programmer-in-berlin-finances/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 05:03:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/programmer-in-berlin-finances/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part 3 of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/programmer-in-berlin/&#34;&gt;5-part series&lt;/a&gt; detailing what I wish I had known as an&#xA;American programmer moving to Berlin. This page details some awfulness with respect to&#xA;finances and taxes while being abroad.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;salary&#34;&gt;Salary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think for a lot of American programmers, especially ones coming out of FAANGs, this is a&#xA;huge consideration. The salaries in Europe just aren&amp;rsquo;t the same as they are in the US, or&#xA;especially in the Bay Area.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programmer in Berlin: Moving In</title>
      <link>https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/programmer-in-berlin-moving-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 05:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/programmer-in-berlin-moving-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part 2 of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/programmer-in-berlin/&#34;&gt;5-part series&lt;/a&gt; detailing what I wish I had known as an&#xA;American programmer moving to Berlin. This page details some practicalities of actually&#xA;moving to a different country, from getting a work visa to making sure your electronics&#xA;work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-visa&#34;&gt;Work visa&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve decided to make the move, one of the first things you need to do is secure a&#xA;work visa. This will go a little differently depending on your situation:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programmer in Berlin: Motivation / Before the move</title>
      <link>https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/programmer-in-berlin-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 05:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/programmer-in-berlin-motivation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part 1 of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/programmer-in-berlin/&#34;&gt;5-part series&lt;/a&gt; detailing what I wish I had known as an&#xA;American programmer moving to Berlin. This page explores the motivation to move to a&#xA;different country, some ways to guide your decision making, and what you might want to&#xA;establish before moving to make your future life easier.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-you-should-do-it&#34;&gt;Why you should do it&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re probably not going to do something just because someone online tells you to do it,&#xA;but I might as well give you some motivation on why moving is a good idea.&#xA;There are the more abstract reasons, like &amp;ldquo;living abroad expands how you think about the&#xA;world,&amp;rdquo; lifestyle/political reasons like experiencing life in a place with universal&#xA;healthcare, and more prosaic reasons like enjoying techno music. Personally, I just really&#xA;liked Berlin and was at a point in my life and career where making such a move was&#xA;possible &amp;ndash; things aligned, and I knew that such an opportunity wouldn&amp;rsquo;t happen again&#xA;soon. In any case it&amp;rsquo;s fun and cool!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I wish I had known as a programmer moving to Berlin</title>
      <link>https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/programmer-in-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 05:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/programmer-in-berlin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve passed my seven year mark living in Berlin, Germany, and I thought it would be&#xA;worthwhile to reflect on it and write down some of the things I wished I had known before&#xA;moving from the US.&#xA;Building a new life in a different country is a tremendous&#xA;amount of work but can also be extremely rewarding.&#xA;My goal isn&amp;rsquo;t to persuade you to move or not to move here, only to give you some&#xA;more information to help you make a decision for yourself or better prepare for a move if&#xA;you&amp;rsquo;ve already decided on it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hire Me</title>
      <link>https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/hire-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:20:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/hire-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;hire-me&#34;&gt;Hire me!&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hello! I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer looking for a new job in Berlin (or remote)!&#xA;I have 15 years of professional experience in small, medium and large companies, and am&#xA;looking forward to seeing how I can use that experience to help further your team&amp;rsquo;s goals.&#xA;I have listed more about about myself below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If I seem&#xA;like a good fit, please contact me using one of the methods listed in the &amp;ldquo;contact&amp;rdquo;&#xA;section. Even if you&amp;rsquo;re not hiring, I&amp;rsquo;m up for a coffee or chat if you&amp;rsquo;re in Berlin.&#xA;Looking forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MacOS Nix Setup (an alternative to Homebrew)</title>
      <link>https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/macos-nix-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 23:58:35 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/macos-nix-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently got a new Macbook, and began setting up the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nixos.org/&#34;&gt;Nix&lt;/a&gt; package manager to&#xA;install my developer toolset. I mainly did this to try and have a working setup without&#xA;installing &lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh/&#34;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt;. Since I ran into a few issues, I wanted to briefly&#xA;document what I did and why in case others wanted to try the same.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-nix-and-why-not-homebrew-or-macports&#34;&gt;Why Nix? (and why not Homebrew or MacPorts?)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The short answer: hype.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The long answer: I&amp;rsquo;ve been frustrated with Homebrew&amp;rsquo;s user experience for years now, and&#xA;used this opportunity to start afresh. The default non-Homebrew answer is the venerable&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.macports.org/&#34;&gt;MacPorts&lt;/a&gt;, which has been around for quite a while. Most people who aren&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;functional programming or build system nerds should probably use MacPorts, as it has been&#xA;around long enough to have good support documentation floating around the internet.&#xA;Unfortunately I&amp;rsquo;m a sucker for hermetic builds &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, so I decided to try&#xA;Nix.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>German for Programmers</title>
      <link>https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/german-for-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 21:37:26 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedchicken.github.io/post/german-for-programmers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After 2 years of learning German I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that, for the most part, you can&#xA;go a long way by mapping foreign concepts to ones that you already know. In&#xA;particular, I&amp;rsquo;ve had success mapping aspects of German grammar to programming&#xA;concepts I use every day. After all, programmers deal with weird grammars all&#xA;the time, why not take advantage of that skill?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;gendered-nouns-forward-error-correction&#34;&gt;Gendered nouns: forward error correction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Probably the first difficulty people run into when leaning German is memorizing&#xA;the gender of each noun and &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.redd.it/hotye1wdbg511.jpg&#34;&gt;properly declining&lt;/a&gt; that noun&amp;rsquo;s articles&#xA;when used in a sentence. While the grammar is mostly regular here, two things&#xA;make this challenging: the nonsensical assignment of genders to nouns&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&#xA;and the sheer amount of memorization required to select the correct declension&#xA;once the gender of the noun is known.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
